<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Covid-19 Handbook</string>
    <string name="first">Drug</string>
    <string name="second">A lot drugs</string>
    <string name="name_langs">English</string>

    <string name="info_1"><![CDATA[Coronaviruses are a large family of viruses that can cause various diseases in humans - from the common cold to SARS. Viruses from this family also cause a number of diseases in animals.
<br><br>
The new coronavirus is a special strain of coronaviruses not previously detected in humans. Due to the fact that only a few cases of the disease are registered to date, information on the transmission, severity and clinical impact of the infection is very limited.]]></string>
    <string name="info_2"><![CDATA[<br><br><b>Virus source</b><br>]]></string>
    <string name="info_3"><![CDATA[MERS-CoV is a zoonotic virus, that is, a virus transmitted between animals and humans. Studies have shown that people become infected through direct and indirect contact with infected camels. MERS-CoV was detected in one-humped camels in several countries in the Middle East, Africa and South Asia.
<br><br>
The origin of this virus is not fully known, but according to the analysis of various genomes of the virus, it is believed that it arose among bats and was transmitted to one-humped camels in the distant past.]]></string>
    <string name="info_4"><![CDATA[<br><br><b>Key facts</b><br>]]></string>
    <string name="info_5"><![CDATA[<ul>
          <li>&nbsp; Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS) is a viral respiratory disease caused by the new coronavirus (Middle East Respiratory Syndrome or MERS-CoV), which was first diagnosed in Saudi Arabia in 2012.</li>
          <li>&nbsp; Coronaviruses are a large family of viruses that can cause illnesses from the common cold to severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS).</li>
          <li>&nbsp; Typical symptoms of MERS include fever, coughing, and shortness of breath. Pneumonia is common, but not always present. Gastroenterological symptoms, including diarrhea, are also recorded.</li>
          <li>&nbsp; Some laboratory-confirmed cases of MERS-CoV infection are reported as asymptomatic, that is, patients have no clinical symptoms, but the results of laboratory testing of samples taken from them are positive for MERS-CoV. Most of these asymptomatic cases have been identified as a result of active monitoring of patient contacts with laboratory-confirmed disease.</li>
          <li>&nbsp; Approximately 35% of registered MERS-CoV patients died.</li>
          <li>&nbsp; Although the majority of human cases of MERS-CoV are attributable to the transmission of infection between people in medical institutions, the current scientific evidence suggests that one-humped camels are the main reservoir host for MERS-CoV and a source of infection for humans of MERS. However, the exact role of camels in the transmission of the virus and the specific transmission route (s) are unknown.</li>
          <li>&nbsp; It is assumed that the virus does not pass freely from person to person, unless there is close contact between them, for example, when a patient is provided with medical care without protective equipment. Outbreaks related to the provision of medical care occurred in a number of countries, and the largest of them - in Saudi Arabia, the United Arab Emirates and the Republic of Korea.</li>
          </ul>]]></string>

    <string name="syms_1"><![CDATA[<b>Symptoms</b><br>]]></string>

    <string name="syms_2"><![CDATA[The clinical manifestations of MERS-CoV infection range from the absence of symptoms (asymptomatic course) or mild respiratory symptoms to severe acute respiratory illness and death. A typical picture of MERS-CoV is high fever, coughing and shortness of breath. Usually, but not always, pneumonia is detected. Gastroenterological symptoms, including diarrhea, are also recorded. In severe illness, respiratory arrest may occur, which requires mechanical ventilation and assistance in the intensive care unit. The virus appears to cause a more severe course of the disease in older people, those with weakened immune systems and those suffering from chronic diseases such as cancer, chronic lung diseases and diabetes.
<br><br>
Approximately 35% of patients with MERS have died, but this rate may be overestimated compared to the actual mortality rate, since mild cases of MERS can remain overlooked by existing surveillance systems, and mortality rates are calculated only among laboratory-confirmed patients before gaining deeper knowledge about this disease. a disease.]]></string>
    <string name="syms_3"><![CDATA[<br><br><b>What are the symptoms of a disease caused by a new coronavirus?</b><br>]]></string>

    <string name="syms_4"><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li>&nbsp; Feeling tired</li>
                    <li>&nbsp; Labored breathing</li>
                    <li>&nbsp; Heat</li>
                    <li>&nbsp; Cough and / or sore throat</li>
                    <li>&nbsp; Symptoms are largely similar to many respiratory diseases, often mimic the common cold, and may be like the flu.</li>
                    <li>&nbsp; If you have similar symptoms, consider the following:<br><br>
                    Have you been to high-risk areas (China and surrounding regions) in the past two weeks?<br><br>
Have you been in contact with someone who has been visiting high-risk areas (China and surrounding regions) in the past two weeks?<br><br>
If the answer to these questions is positive, the symptoms should be treated as carefully as possible.</li></ul>]]></string>
    <string name="info_title">Info</string>
    <string name="syms_title">Symptoms</string>
</resources>